YOUQING SHAO

(617)306-5019 | yshaots@bu.edu | Boston, MA | Full-Stack SDE

SUMMARY

I had worked in Internet company in Beijing for 3 years. I had project experiences in front-end, back-end, microservices and big project architecture. Seeking for a full-time internship software developer position starting at Summer 2023.

EDUCATION

Boston University

Boston, MA

Master of Science in Computer Science

Sept 2022 – Dec 2023

JiangXi Agricultural University

Jiangxi, China

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sept 2016 - May 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- * Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node, Python, C++, HTML5, CSS3 (code line: More than 120,000)
- * Database and Cloud: MySQL, MongoDB, AWS EC2, Heroku
- * Frameworks: Vue, React, Express, JQuery, Umi, Spring Boot, Mybatis, Django, Antd, MaterialsUI, Vite, Webpack, Junit
- * Tools: Git, Charles, VS Code, IDEA, VirtualBox, Postman, Swagger, Figma, Navicat, Docker, Sketch

WORK EXPERIENCE

DiDi (Uber's biggest competitor)

Full-time

Beijing, China

Senior software Engineer in the Internationalization-Experience Center Platform Technology Department

Apr 2021 - Aug 2022

- * Independently completed the development of the component library 1.0(provided quick support for driver-side), 2.0(covered driver-side, client-side, outside H5, with the explicit construction process and official technical website)
- * Independently developed the Linkee (car hailing platform) official website with an SEO score of 91 and the registrations of 150,000, including Multi language support, EJS template complier, PC and mobile adaptation and SRE configuration website: https://liggyglobal.com/
- * Developed gaxios(sdk) to invert request, common parameters, and trace-id injection (H5 page usage coverage reaches 90%)
- * Optimized the simultaneous display of drivers and passengers, and increase the completion rate of Mexico by 4.7%
- * Cooperated to develop the quick-bolt (low code platform), survey-test (questionnaire platform), responsible for the development of some front-end pages and node servers built with an express framework, developed two notify robots to analyze relevant data

Alibaba Full-time software Engineer in the Fliggy Framework Technology Department.

Beijing, China
May 2020 - Apr 2021

- * Cooperated and Completed CMS architecture design, authority management, approval system design and development
- * Finished map module in Universal Beijing Resort mini program, including map main page, route planning and navigation
- * Supported for pictures, cards, content analysis, request, fonts, ticket reservation component development
- * Cooperated with Taobao technology, Amap technology and Alipay technology to develop and complete the embedding of ecommerce, customer service and ticket system, accessible for four platforms individually
- * Cooperated to develop 360 panoramic garden tour and call of intelligent identification system
- * Developed the ma-groode (a four terminal test code tool for applets), greatly improved the efficiency of QA

SCHOOL PROJECT AND OTHERS

- * Library CMS: completed front-end, back-end and database independently (java + springboot + mysql + mybatis + Junit)
- * Rxcellent: Cooperated with course group (UI, SDE, QA and PM) to complete drugs ordering platform. (node + TS)
- * Flea Market: Cooperated with friends to develop a second-hand platform in BU (Python + Django + Mongo)
- * Internship Project: Text annotation system, Voice annotation system (Audio waveform drawing and automatic annotation), Project management system, Data platform (Data summary and distribution)